Fangqing (Francis) Yu

Phone: (626) 321-5848 Website: https://fangqingyu.github.io

Email: fangqingyu2010@gmail.com

DATA ANALYST

Bilingual Data Analyst with experience in Quality Control (QC), Manufacturing and Statistical Process Control with demonstrated proficiency in working with large data sets and reporting tools. Three years of experience working in Biotech. Familiar with HIPPA, cGMP regulations and SOPs. Passionate about Data Science and BI. Looking to join or work closely with a data engineering and product team or a team of data scientists. Fluent in Chinese.

Relevant Skills

- Demonstrated proficiency in Excel, Macros, VBA scripting for data processing, formatting, pivot tables, graphing and charting and other MS Office software
- Proficient in coding with Python and ETL strategy for data acquisition, manipulation, transformation, cleaning (Pandas) and visualization (Matplotlib, Plotly)
- Ability to access data from variety of sources including RDMS (MySQL), NoSQL(MongoDB), web scraping (BeautifulSoup) and API.
- Ability to use advanced data storage and retrieval tools such as Python SQLAlchemy and PyMongo
- Proficient in SQL for performing querying, data aggregations, joins, filter and ability to develop complex queries, sub-queries
- Knowledge of HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Flask and Github for building and publishing webpages
- DOM manipulation and interactive dashboarding with JavaScript

EXPERIENCE

Genalyte, Inc., San Diego, CA QC Data Analyst

2016 - Present

Perform a variety of activities including data acquisition and processing to support various departments in analyzing and interpreting results for experiments, execution of protocols and other projects.

- Design and implement report templates for Standard Operating Procedures (SOPs).
- Designed and put in place the company's SOPs for QC Lot Verification and Instrument Validation analysis procedures
- Automated the reporting process for periodic reports including production metrics, QC inspection and instrument validation reports
- Collaborate with Operations, Assay Development, Engineering and Manufacturing departments to provide data reporting support
- Acquire (retrieve) data from existing data environment to deliver reporting solution
- Validate, interpret and visualize raw experiment data using statistical techniques

- Develop macros and scripts to process, manipulate data, create visualizations and deliver results in client-requested formats or populate matrices (databases, spreadsheets) suitable for tasks.
- Attend meetings to keep informed of development and manufacturing priorities and activities.
- Maintain and update relevant SOPs for data review and reporting, as needed.

Q2 Trading, LLC, Albany, NY Intern / Contract Market Research Analyst

2012 and 2015

Helped the company expand their existing customer base by marketing to potential customers.

- Researched and reported on market conditions in company's strategic market.
- Collected, organized and interpreted data using software tools, generating reports on prospects and performance.
- Assisted sales and management with day-to-day tasks.
- Compiled, implemented and validated a databank of potential clients in the region.
- Developed posters, guides and classroom materials to help employees learn basic Chinese language to more effectively penetrate potential markets.
- Helped initiate, design and organize a regional trade show targeting local retail businesses.

Learning Assistance Center, Pasadena City College, Pasadena, CA Tutor

2010 - 2011

Tutored students on subjects such as math, statistics and introductory physics.

International Student Office, Pasadena City College, Pasadena, CA Student Worker

2009 - 2010

Proofed and processed thousands of student information records in an efficient and accurate manner.

- Created reports on prospective, newly-admitted, and continuing students on a weekly basis.
- Informed students regarding government laws and regulations, and deadlines.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science – Applied Mathematics Statistics and Probability, University of California San Diego (UCSD), San Diego, CA (Minor in Economics)

CERTIFICATIONS

Data Science and Visualization, UCSD Extension